Welcome to Mr Pinas' home,
Marciano Pinas. Mrs Derks called us.
A sweet but over-concerned neighbour.
You know the type. What a coincidence.
Good of you to come so quickly.
I’m Jeanine. Mr Pinas is a lovely man.
He used to ask me over for dinner.
He was a great cook.
But since his wife died suddenly last year
he has deteriorated.
The dear old man is so confused, lately.
I do his shopping,
but still he keeps losing weight.
Mr Pinas, it's me. You have a visitor.
Hello, Mr Pinas. I've brought somebody
to have a chat with you.
Who are you?
Do you know what's wrong
with Mr Pinas?
You have three minutes to work it out.
Good luck.
What are you doing?
I'm afraid you didn't succeed.
There is often more to a situation
than you initially think.
You must get an overview
and take the right decision.
Come on, you can do it.
No, there is no guessing
in geriatric care.
What are you doing here?
I don't need anything.
It's already in the evening.
Did that other lady also come with you?
General Practitioner J.P. Terpstra
020 - 7604600
Thursday.
Morning, afternoon, evening.
Look at this. All the food has gone off
and he hasn't eaten any of it.
What do I know about Mr Pinas?
Last year, his wife died suddenly.
She wasn't from Surinam, by the way.
His family is in Surinam. He has trouble
walking, that's why I do the shopping.
Nowadays, all his food is going off.
And he's forgetting so many things.
But that's due
to the early-stage dementia.
I collect his medication
because he refuses home care.
What else?
He's seeing things that aren't here.
That's all I can tell you.
So, what do you think?
Is Mr Pinas eating and drinking enough?
Is he taking his medication properly?
Not eating and drinking, not knowing
whether it's day or night.
What do you make of it?
Have you worked it out?
Please tell us.
You could do that but be careful.
Don't make any snap decisions.
Take your time with Mr Pinas.
Yes, indeed. First, you get an overview
and then you act.
What's wrong with Mr Pinas?
The fridge is full
but Mr Pinas clearly isn't.
His dementia plays a role
but there is more to this.
Very good. His fridge is full
but Mr Pinas clearly isn't.
He has symptoms of a delirium.
You know enough to consult the GP
about how to stabilize his situation.
Final question:
What is your follow-up plan?
Mr Pinas needs more than a clock. But
a hospital admission isn't needed either.
Think ahead.
Well done. With a plan
for home care and support...
and the neighbour's assistance
you can really help Mr Pinas.
It's just a first step towards
getting Mr Pinas back on track again.
Care to visit another client?
You're here now.