Hello, good of you to come. What a cool
bike, that will get you from A to B.
This is Mr and Mrs van Zand's house.
They've lived here for 40 years
and they don't want to leave.
Mr van Zand has COPD and rheumatism.
He hardly leaves the house.
But Mrs van Zand
takes good care of him.
Are you here already?
Well, you might as well come in.
Coby van Zand.
Cees van Zand, hello.
And, how do you assess this situation?
You have three minutes to work it out.
Good luck.
Are you okay?
-Of course.
Are you sure?
I'm afraid you didn't succeed.
In geriatric care,
there is often more to a situation.
You must get an overview
and take the right decision.
Try again.
Good luck, you can do it.
There's no guessing in geriatric care.
Could you make us a cup of coffee?
Normally, my wife does it.
I'm not capable of much anymore, so
she does everything around the house.
Far too much, really. But
she's stubborn, so what can you do.
No, I'm fine.
We enjoy doing everything ourselves
while we still can.
And we're managing fine.
We don't need anybody's help. Do we?
10:40 hairdresser.
Interesting, normally you shake hands
with your right hand.
There are broken bits everywhere.
Do you think Mrs van Zand can manage?
It won't be cleared up soon.
It's time to take action.
Do you know? Let's continue.
What's the first thing you do now?
No, I'm afraid not.
Mrs van Zand has severe osteoporosis.
Maybe you should take that into account.
And yes, that is the correct answer.
This lady may have damaged her arm
due to osteoporosis.
The GP should take a look at it.
But there is more to this.
What is the real problem?
No, I'm afraid not.
It seems obvious but you must get
an overview of the entire situation.
Try again.
Yes, good observation. Mrs van Zand
is an overburdened carer. Carry on.
Last question:
What is your long-term plan?
That's a very drastic measure
and unnecessary.
Mr and Mrs van Zand
can stay living at home.
But you have to draw up a plan together.
Good plan.
Talk to Mr and Mrs and
draw up a plan for home care.
So they can keep living at home
while Mrs van Zand gets support.
Help her together with your colleagues.
Have you done all the cases yet?
You'll see that a registered nurse has
a very important job. Think about it.