Hello, good to see you.
We're on the rehabilitation ward
where Mr Davids is staying.
He had hip surgery last week.
Normally, Mr Davids is a cheerful man.
A bit like me, really.
But you'll see that he's not himself,
today. Here we are.
Somebody else again?
Okay, what's wrong with Mr Davids?
You have three minutes to work it out.
Good luck.
I'm afraid you didn't succeed.
In geriatric care,
there is often more to a situation.
You must get an overview
and take the right decision.
Try again.
Come on, you can do it.
No, guessing isn't allowed.
I don't get it. Normally, I can do
a crossword puzzle in no time at all.
But now...
Lovely, but it gives you sticky fingers.
Mr Davids has kept
his diary properly. Hasn't he?
To measure is to know, so they say.
Get well soon.
Dear dad, get well soon.
We'll come to visit you.
Did you work it out? Great. So tell me:
What's the underlying problem?
That's not the right answer. Take a look
at the clues. I'm sure you'll work it out.
Yes, Mr Davids has diabetes
and he probably had some cake.
His sticky fingers biased
blood glucose measurements.
That's why he injected too much insulin.
What do you do now?
No, Mr Davids is hypoglycaemic,
his blood sugar must go up quickly.
Painkillers and insulin
will only make matters worse.
What's the very first thing you do now?
Yes, very good.
With a glass of lemonade and a sandwich
he'll soon feel much better.
Last question: How can we prevent
this from happening in future?
No, the elderly aren't children.
Telling Mr Davids off and taking away
his sweets, is that a good idea?
Well done, obviously it's just
the first step to help Mr Davids.
See?
There is often more to it than you think.
You have the overview, you decide.